MARTINS SILINS

Mob: 07867256957

Email: martins.silins123@hotmail.com

CT9 2LA

PROFILE

My past work experience has provided me with a solid foundation of management and administrative skills. I have experience in office management, research and project delivery. I have developed excellent and effective communication skills through my studies of MA in EU International Relations and Diplomacy together with an active engagement in GCDC/GCRF COMPASS Project, Kent Model United Nations (KENTMUN) and in-class and University nationwide negotiations simulations. I consider myself a great communicator with the ability to build critical relationships with colleagues, staff, and peers.

KEY SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

Negotiation and Mediation

- As a KENTMUN member, I have assumed Russian Federations Diplomatic service representative role, where I have to negotiate terms and agreements with other representatives of their assumed states.
- One of my modules requires me to participate in simulations between my colleagues from my course and other Universities nationwide; topics involved are border disputes, arms deals and peace negotiation and mediation between small and large states.

Research and Development

- I am currently involved in the University of Kent research project (GCRF COMPASS), where I am researching the Central Asian energy sector and 'European Union Central Asian Strategy 2019'.
- While working as an office admin, I researched up to date driving school policies after that I compiled most relevant findings into comprehensive booklets/manuals for pupils and instructors.
- As an IT Engineer, I had to do a lot of research on Fujitsu clients and their IT equipment on top of that I also was required to continuously develop my knowledge in latest technologies and in-house and Microsoft applications.

Cross-Cultural Management

- During my employment period and studies at the University of Kent, I was liaising with a vast variety of individuals from different cultural and social backgrounds.
- My studies and engagement in KENTMUN provided me with necessary International Relations skills on different cultures, their history and political and religious views.

Flexibility and Adaptability

- During my full-time studies of MA in EU International Relations and Diplomacy besides of delivering essays and researching for COMPASS project I was also involved in societies, like KENTMUN, student media "Inquire" and representing student interests as a Student representative for School of World and European Languages.
- During my employment period at Fujitsu Services, I was required to travel daily from one client to another while supplying them with equipment upgrades and repairs or providing them with the necessary skills on how to use their newly installed equipment.

Teamwork

- My first few months for Fujitsu Services was a project delivery where I worked together with five to eight other
 engineers; we had to liaise and share our responsibilities equally and efficiently based on our skills and
 availability.
- As a student, we have to work on different kind of projects and simulations for our degree. One of them was to draft a policy brief on extraterritorial processing for refugees where we scored top marks.
- Managing roles and responsibilities in societies require an ability to work in teams while following your own goals and needs.

Project delivery

- While working for Fujitsu Services, I successfully closed multiple projects for companies and institutions like the Ministry of Defence in Portsmouth, Morrison's, Boots, South Eastern Trains, Hewlett-Packard, and Deutsche Bank in London.
- Currently, I am participating in the University of Kent GCRF COMPASS research-based project.

QUALIFICATIONS AND PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- Sep 2017 Sep 2019: MA EU International Relations and Diplomacy; University of Kent, UK.
- July 2016 June 2017: Level 3 Foundation Certificate in HR Practice; Avado Learning, UK
- Sep 2007 July 2011: Bachelor (Honours) Degree Social Pedagogy; Liepajas Universitate, LV.

Professional Courses / Training:

- University of Kent Global Challenges Doctoral Centre Training Programme
- University of Kent Graduate School Skills Programme
- CompTIA Network+ N10-006;
- Unique IT Training (Unique Certificate in Systems & Networking (UCSN));
- Notebook and Desktop Service Engineer Course;
- The Health & Safety Group LTD (Training Course);
- MS Office 2016;

WORK EXPERIENCE

SDIP - Civil Service Fast Stream for Department of Transport [July 2018 – Aug.2018]

Key Responsibilities: Attended meetings with policymakers and operations management teams.

Office Administrator - Learn & Pass in Kent [Sep.2016 – Nov.2017]

Key Responsibilities: Managed Instructors and student database, prepared contacts, created and updated "Learn & Pass in Kent" booklets, manuals and Facebook page.

WEX – Department for Work and Pensions [June 2016 – Sep. 2016]

Key Responsibilities: Assisted work coaches with document sorting or printing/copying, prepared registration documents and helped customers to complete online registration forms.

Technology Support Specialist/IT Engineer – Fujitsu Services Engineering Services LTD (FSESL) [Oct.2013 – Dec.2015] **Key Responsibilities:** Provided diverse technical IT support, ensured quality assurance by prioritising effective communication and working closely with each stakeholder to resolve any issues or unplanned requirements that have arisen during their utilisation.

Data Processing Clerk – SIA Baltik IT [Oct.2010 - Feb.2012]

Key Responsibilities: Worked with confidential files and payments for Italian company ENEL;

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Interests:

- COMPASS Project (https://research.kent.ac.uk/gcrf-compass/#);
- KENTMUN Model United Nations (Representative role of the Russian Federation);
- InQuire Student Media (Opinion Writer);
- School of World and European Languages (Student Representative);
- International Relations and Conflict